<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mathurin Choblet</title>
    <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mathurin Choblet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 13:01:02 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mchoblet.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>University</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 13:01:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/university/</guid>
      <description>A collection of presentations and reports I did throughout my studies.
Master thesis (2022) My thesis is about applying methods from Data Assimilation to climate model data and terrestial proxies (speleothemes and icecores) (I will for sure do a blog post at one point)
 Outline presentation of the project Update presentation (focus on computational efficiency of different type of Ensemble Kalman Filters) Paper discussion in our climate variability Journal club.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog now online</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/post/blog_online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 17:54:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/post/blog_online/</guid>
      <description>My blog is now online! So this is it, I finally managed to publish my own blog. Using HUGO and Github pages it was actually simpler than I thought.
In the last years I always thought of having my own website, for sharing some stuff about things I do, maybe it is of interest to you.
For instance I have accompanied many international students who are starting at Heidelberg University. As some questions used to come up everytime, I thought that some basic information from a students perspective should be written on the internet, so this is what the entry Get started in Heidelberg is for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freetour</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/freetour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 18:05:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/freetour/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 13:01:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Mathurin (aka Mathu or Mathi), physics master student at Heidelberg University, currently working on Data Assimilation with climate model output and proxy data for the last millenium as part of the STACY/Climatology group based at Tuebingen university.
During my studies I have been a student representative at the local student council for many years, where I got involved in university commitees, organized events and course evaluations and helped new students to get started in their studies together with many great people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started in Heidelberg</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/get-started/</guid>
      <description>Information for new students in Heidelberg Hello visitor, whereever you come from!
If you&amp;rsquo;re a new student arriving in Heidelberg from abroad this is the blog you were looking for. I helped some new students in Heidelberg during the last years and wanted to gather the most imporant information once and for all at one place.
My focus lies on sharing personal experiences and letting you save money whenever possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hummus Recipe</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/post/hummus-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/post/hummus-recipe/</guid>
      <description>Why put the millionth Hummus Recipe online? Couldn’t you come up with something more creative? Well, for my first blog post I wanted to start with something that I think I know how to do. Probably Hummus is the thing I’ve cost most in my life at a variety of events. Hummus is simple to make, nourishing, healthy and delicious. After making your own Hummus you will never reach for supermarket Hummus again.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>