<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>university on Mathurin Choblet</title>
    <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/tags/university/</link>
    <description>Recent content in university on Mathurin Choblet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mchoblet.github.io/tags/university/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My experience at the European Geoscience Union General Assembly 2023</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/post/egu_2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/post/egu_2023/</guid>
      <description>More than a month ago, I had the privilege of attending the EGU 2023 in Vienna, which marked my first scientific conference. In this blog post, I want to summarize my experiences of presenting a poster and working as a conference assistant, which kept me busy throughout the week. I never thought I would get such a high dose of Geosciences during one week.
What is the EGU? The European Geoscience Union General Assembly (EGU) is the second-largest geosciences conference globally, following its American counterpart, the AGU.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to (not) Give a Short Scientific Talk</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/post/how_not_to/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/post/how_not_to/</guid>
      <description>Being a conference assistant at the European Geoscience Union (EGU) General Assembly 2023 in Vienna (https://www.egu23.eu/), I had the opportunity to witness around 200 scientific talks due to my job in the &amp;ldquo;lecture rooms.&amp;rdquo; My main responsibilities included downloading and opening the PowerPoint/PDF slides of the speakers, adjusting the technical setup, managing the timer, handling the Zoom session for online participants, and communicating with the conveners who led the usually two-hour-long sessions consisting of ten 8-minute talks + 2 minutes for questions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finished my master&#39;s thesis!</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/post/master/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/post/master/</guid>
      <description>I finally handed in my Physics master&amp;rsquo;s thesis at Heidelberg University! Let me first say thank you to all the wonderful people at the STACY/SPACY group at Heidelberg and Tübingen University that made my work possible and made the last year such a pleasant experience.
In the last year, I&amp;rsquo;ve tested a statistical method named Data Assimilation to reconstruct the climate of the last millennium by fusing information from speleothems and ice cores and so-called isotope-enabled climate models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First guided tours through the old town of Heidelberg</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/post/firsttours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/post/firsttours/</guid>
      <description>After thinking about the idea for a few months, I finally started guiding small groups of Spanish speaking visitors and will give my fourth tour tomorrow.
I advertise my so-called Freetours (people can give whatever tip they like in the end) via the usual platforms Guruwalk and Freetour.com, where I offer two tours a week, although I did not always have people yet.
Now that I have gathered some reviews on these sites it should be easier to gather an audience (although I think that a small group of up to ~8 people is most enjoyable for everyone).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>University</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 13:01:02 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/university/</guid>
      <description>Publications and conference contributions A continental reconstruction of hydroclimatic variability in South America during the past 2000 years (2023, in preparation) EGU 2023 conference abstract about my work on Paleoclimate Data ASsimilation Graduate Education at the University of Liège Coming soon! Master My thesis was about applying methods from Data Assimilation to climate model data and climate archives (speleothemes and icecores) for reconstructing climate fields of the past 2000 years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get started in Heidelberg</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/get-started/</guid>
      <description>Information for new students in Heidelberg Updated last time in February 2023
Hello visitor, where ever you come from!
If you&amp;rsquo;re a new student arriving in Heidelberg from abroad I hope this is the blog you were looking for. I helped some new students in Heidelberg during the last years and wanted to gather the most important information once and for all at one place.
My focus lies on sharing personal experiences and letting you save money whenever possible.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
