<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tops on Mathurin Choblet</title>
    <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tops on Mathurin Choblet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 18:09:12 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mchoblet.github.io/top/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Miscellaneous</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 18:09:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/misc/</guid>
      <description>Texts written for the conference booklet of the physics student conference ZAPF in Heidelberg (in 2018) about the history of our University, the Faculty,deutsche Physik and the student committee our Faculty Presentation about the privatization of water resources in Bolivia for Geography class at High School (2015) Jugend forscht (Young STEM researchers competition project) about examining the moment a body lifts off an inclined plane together with Christian Hufnagel (2015).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Archive</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 13:01:02 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/archive/</guid>
      <description>Older things on this blog.
Get started as a student Heidelberg, a collection of useful information Heidelberg Free Tours in spanish language miscellaneous things) </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>University</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 13:01:02 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/university/</guid>
      <description>Publications and conference contributions A continental reconstruction of hydroclimatic variability in South America during the past 2000 years (2023, in preparation) EGU 2023 conference abstract about my work on Paleoclimate Data ASsimilation Graduate Education at the University of Liège Coming soon! Master My thesis was about applying methods from Data Assimilation to climate model data and climate archives (speleothemes and icecores) for reconstructing climate fields of the past 2000 years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freetour</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/freetour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 18:05:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/freetour/</guid>
      <description>I finished my studies in Heidelberg in December 2022 and don&amp;rsquo;t live there any longer, so I am not giving the tours anymore. I will transfer this webpage into a blogpost about my experiences at some point
(English) In order to practice my Spanish skills and share the fascinating history of Heidelberg, I decided to become an independent tour guide for the summer months of 2022. You can find me on the usual freetour platforms, which I use to promote the tours (in spanish).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 13:01:02 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I’m Mathurin! Glad you found my web page.
I’m currently a PhD student in Oceanography at the University of Liège, working on physical-biogeochemical ocean modeling in the MAST group. My research focuses on modeling sediments in the Black Sea of both biogenic and mineral origin.
With a background in Physics from the University of Heidelberg, where I completed both my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s and Master&amp;rsquo;s degrees, my journey in climate science began during my time at the STACY/Climatology group group.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get started in Heidelberg</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/get-started/</guid>
      <description>Information for new students in Heidelberg Updated last time in February 2023
Hello visitor, where ever you come from!
If you&amp;rsquo;re a new student arriving in Heidelberg from abroad I hope this is the blog you were looking for. I helped some new students in Heidelberg during the last years and wanted to gather the most important information once and for all at one place.
My focus lies on sharing personal experiences and letting you save money whenever possible.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
