<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tops on Mathurin Choblet</title>
    <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tops on Mathurin Choblet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 13:01:02 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mchoblet.github.io/top/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>University</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/university/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 13:01:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/university/</guid>
      <description>A collection of presentations and reports I did throughout my studies.
During my master thesis (2022) My thesis is about applying methods from Data Assimilation to climate model data and terrestial proxies (speleothemes and icecores) (I will for sure do a blog post at one point)
 Outline presentation for my project Update presentation (focus on computational efficiency of different type of Ensemble Kalman Filters) Paper discussion in our climate variability Journal club.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freetour</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/freetour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 18:05:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/freetour/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 13:01:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Mathurin (aka Mathu or Mathi), physics master student at Heidelberg University, currently working on Data Assimilation with climate model output and proxy data for the last millenium as part of the STACY/Climatology group based at Tuebingen university.
Starting from May 2022 I plan offer guided Freetours in spanish language in Heidelberg. Besides hoping to improve my communicative and narrative skills, I hope to be able to tell interesting stories to my audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started in Heidelberg</title>
      <link>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mchoblet.github.io/top/get-started/</guid>
      <description>Information for new students in Heidelberg Hello visitor, whereever you come from!
If you&amp;rsquo;re a new student arriving in Heidelberg from abroad this is the blog you were looking for. I helped some new students in Heidelberg during the last years and wanted to gather the most imporant information once and for all at one place.
My focus lies on sharing personal experiences and letting you save money whenever possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>